<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/</link><description>Recent content on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 04:52:30 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Author</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/author/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 02:07:31 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/author/</guid><description>I am John Doe. And I can confirm that this is the best theme ever!</description></item><item><title>Admin Panel</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 02:07:30 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/admin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>All Sections</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/sections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 02:07:30 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/sections/</guid><description/></item><item><title>7 Github repos that will make You Lol</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/github-repos-that-will-make-you-lol/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/github-repos-that-will-make-you-lol/</guid><description>Call me a nerd, but I find GitHub repositories to be entertaining. Here are some of my favorite ones that truly made me LOL. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to run any code or that sort of stuff. Just go through the READMEs.
1. hacker-scripts github.com/NARKOZ/hacker-scripts This is a story about a guy who left his job. His colleagues go through his legacy and found things they never imagined they would find.</description></item><item><title>Biological names used in computer science</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/biological-names-used-in-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/biological-names-used-in-computer-science/</guid><description>Once one of my biology teachers (boma Mizan :p ) said that biological names are used everywhere in technology. I suddenly recalled that memory and now I&amp;rsquo;m making a list of every biological name used in technology.
Amazon: Amazon is a rainforest in South America. Amazon is an American company focusing on e-commerce. Anaconda: Anaconda is a snake. Anaconda is a free and open-source distribution of the Python programming language for scientific computation.</description></item><item><title>Kali as a regular operating system</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</guid><description>If you are an aspiring pentester you should definitely use Kali Linux and make it your primary OS. Switching to a new OS can be a very hard decision to make. Concerns such as whether you can do your regular work may rise. It has been quite a while (3 years) since I am using Kali as my primary OS and here are my experiences with it.
If you are shifting from a Windows environment and have no prior experience with Linux operating systems it&amp;rsquo;s best not to move to Kali just yet.</description></item><item><title>How to be a hacker with Kali</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered Kali Linux and thinking about how you can hack with it, you probably can&amp;rsquo;t and you’re probably walking in the wrong direction.
Kali is not a magic OS that can hack everything. It is just an operating system that comes with preinstalled pentesting tools. Now, you really cannot expect a tool to do everything by itself. You need to understand when it works, where it works, and how it works.</description></item><item><title>5 reasons why Linux needs no antivirus</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-linux-needs-no-antivirus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-linux-needs-no-antivirus/</guid><description>So, maybe you have heard Linux PCs are super safe because they are not affected by viruses. Linux computers are almost immune to viruses. Yes, I said &amp;ldquo;almost&amp;rdquo; immune. But the percentage of PCs being affected is very less, even less than 1%. That is why people say that Linux does not need any antivirus. But why is that have you ever wondered? Here are the top 5 reasons why viruses do not affect Linux.</description></item></channel></rss>