<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>terminal on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/terminal/</link><description>Recent content in terminal on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Awesome terminal tricks to boost your productivity</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/bash-aliases-to-boost-your-productivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/bash-aliases-to-boost-your-productivity/</guid><description>If you are glued to the terminal, you may want to use the following tricks to improve your productivity. These have been a life saver to me. If you&amp;rsquo;re not a terminal user, these tricks will make you love the terminal again.
Contents: Useful aliases Command editing hacks Running past commands Useful commands Useful aliases Copy the lines starting with alias to your ~/.bashrc file to enable them.</description></item><item><title>Npm commands for npm noobs</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/npm-commands-for-npm-noobs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/npm-commands-for-npm-noobs/</guid><description>Since diving more deeply into frontend development, I had troubles adjusting with the node ecosystem, more specifically to npm commands. I just keep on forgetting what the npm commands do. So here are my short notes on them.
Basics $ npm --version # check npm version $ npm install -g npm@latest # update npm Notes: npm packages can be installed locally or globally. global packages are installed with -g flag or - -global flag all installed packages get stored in node_modules folder Package installation # initialize a project that will contain node dependencies $ npm init # search for packages $ npm search package_name # install express package $ npm install express # save package as a developer dependency (e.</description></item><item><title>Difference between bash, shell &amp; terminal</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/bash-vs-shell-vs-terminal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/bash-vs-shell-vs-terminal/</guid><description>People often incorrectly use the terms bash, shell and terminal interchangeably. Whether you are a Linux pro or noob, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve done it too. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you should know when you use these terms the next time.
Shell A shell is a program that takes command from the keyboard and gives them to the operating system to execute.
In short a shell interacts with the OS for you.</description></item><item><title>Bare minimum Multi-tasking guide for the terminal with Tmux</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/multitasking-in-terminal-with-tmux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/multitasking-in-terminal-with-tmux/</guid><description>Have you ever-
SSHed to a server and felt the need of another terminal session because the current one was already running something? SSHed to a server to run a long-running process but couldn&amp;rsquo;t close the terminal because it would terminate the process? Wanted to wok with multi-window terminal like the picture above? Wanted to continue from where you left off your terminal the last time? If your answers to the questions are yes, then Tmux is the tool you need.</description></item></channel></rss>