<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>13 terminal commands that you don't need but deserve</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/terminal-commands-that-you-dont-need-but-deserve/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/terminal-commands-that-you-dont-need-but-deserve/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Linux terminal is not all boring and dull. Spice up your life with these fun and awesome commands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Awesome terminal tricks to boost your productivity</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/awesome-terminal-tricks-to-boost-your-productivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/awesome-terminal-tricks-to-boost-your-productivity/</guid><description>If you are glued to the terminal, you may want to use the following tricks to improve your productivity. These have been a life saver to me. If you&amp;rsquo;re not a terminal user, these tricks will make you love the terminal again.
Contents: Useful aliases Command editing hacks Running past commands Useful commands Useful aliases Copy the lines starting with alias to your ~/.bashrc file to enable them.</description></item><item><title>Difference between bash, shell &amp; terminal</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/bash-vs-shell-vs-terminal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/bash-vs-shell-vs-terminal/</guid><description>People often incorrectly use the terms bash, shell and terminal interchangeably. Whether you are a Linux pro or noob, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve done it too. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you should know when you use these terms the next time.
Shell A shell is a program that takes command from the keyboard and gives them to the operating system to execute.
In short a shell interacts with the OS for you.</description></item><item><title>Bare minimum Multi-tasking guide for the terminal with Tmux</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/multitasking-in-terminal-with-tmux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/multitasking-in-terminal-with-tmux/</guid><description>Have you ever-
SSHed to a server and felt the need of another terminal session because the current one was already running something? SSHed to a server to run a long-running process but couldn&amp;rsquo;t close the terminal because it would terminate the process? Wanted to wok with multi-window terminal like the picture above? Wanted to continue from where you left off your terminal the last time? If your answers to the questions are yes, then Tmux is the tool you need.</description></item><item><title>Kali as a regular operating system</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</guid><description>If you are an aspiring pentester you should definitely use Kali Linux and make it your primary OS. Switching to a new OS can be a very hard decision to make. Concerns such as whether you can do your regular work may rise. It has been quite a while (3 years) since I am using Kali as my primary OS and here are my experiences with it.
If you are shifting from a Windows environment and have no prior experience with Linux operating systems it&amp;rsquo;s best not to move to Kali just yet.</description></item><item><title>5 reasons why Linux needs no antivirus</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-linux-needs-no-antivirus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-linux-needs-no-antivirus/</guid><description>So, maybe you have heard Linux PCs are super safe because they are not affected by viruses. Linux computers are almost immune to viruses. Yes, I said &amp;ldquo;almost&amp;rdquo; immune. But the percentage of PCs being affected is very less, even less than 1%. That is why people say that Linux does not need any antivirus. But why is that have you ever wondered? Here are the top 5 reasons why viruses do not affect Linux.</description></item></channel></rss>