<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>research on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in research on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Guidelines to follow when writing a research paper</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/research-paper-writing-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/research-paper-writing-guidelines/</guid><description>This article is not meant to be a complete guide for paper writing. It is just a cheat sheet for me to follow when I&amp;rsquo;m lost.
A research paper typically has the following sections:
Title Abstract Introduction Literature review Methodology Experiment/Results Acknowledgments (Optional) Conclusion References Appendices (Optional) 1. Title The title should express 3 aspects:
The research domain Purpose of the research The methods used (methodology) Additional tips:</description></item><item><title>How I Accidentally Published a Research Paper at IWOR (ICSE)</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/how-i-published-a-research-paper-at-iwor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/how-i-published-a-research-paper-at-iwor/</guid><description>In our final semester of university, we had a course called &amp;ldquo;Software Metrics.&amp;rdquo; Ths study of software metrics aims at measuring the properties of software. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like this course very much. It was theoretical and a bit boring. I&amp;rsquo;m usually fond of more practical stuff.
In most of our courses, we have to complete a project by the end of the semester. For the software metrics course, we were to build a tool that shows several known metrics of a Java program.</description></item><item><title>DSSE: A software engineering research group in Bangladesh</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/software-engineering-research-and-dsse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/software-engineering-research-and-dsse/</guid><description>If you want to know about research areas in Software Engineering and conferences/journals related to software engineering then this article is for you.
The Distributed Systems and Software Engineering (DSSE) group at the Institute of Information Technology (IIT) is an active group dedicated to Software Engineering research. The group was formed in Bangladesh in 2012 with a few members. Currently, it is a large group consisting of members all around the world.</description></item></channel></rss>