<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software engineering on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/software-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in software engineering on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Github? 15 things you can Do with Github.</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/git/what-is-github/everything-you-can-do-with-github/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/git/what-is-github/everything-you-can-do-with-github/</guid><description>Github is the go to place for storing source code for developers. You are missing out on all the good bits of Github if you only use it for storing your code. Using Github to its full potential will make your life as a developer easier and more productive.</description></item><item><title>Top 3 Formal Method Tools in Software Engineering</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/formal-method-tools-used-in-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/formal-method-tools-used-in-software-engineering/</guid><description>Formal Methods in Software Engineering use mathematical techniques and tools to specify, design, and verify software system behavior. These methods are crucial for dealing with the complexity and criticality of modern software systems operating in dynamic and uncertain environments.</description></item><item><title>Look How Google Writes Technical Documentations! (With Examples)</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/writing-documentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/writing-documentation/</guid><description>Writing software is hard. And writing documentation is harder. No wonder good documentations are hard to find.
But it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this way.
Thankfully I stumbled upon Google&amp;rsquo;s technical document writing course. They formulated it based on their years of experience and numerous researches.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Git Commit Messages</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/git/how-to-write-git-commit-messages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/git/how-to-write-git-commit-messages/</guid><description>A well-written git commit properly conveys what was done in the source code. As software engineering is a team project, being able to convey to others the intent of a commit is very important.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll give a short guideline on how to write commit messages.</description></item><item><title>Cases Used in Programming</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/cases-used-in-programming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/cases-used-in-programming/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard about following camel cases when naming functions and variables. There are more types of cases out there. In this post, we will discover other cases followed in naming conventions and where they are commonly used.</description></item><item><title>How I Suffered by not Doing Requirements Engineering</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/how-i-suffered-by-not-doing-requirements-engineering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/how-i-suffered-by-not-doing-requirements-engineering/</guid><description>Recently one of my relatives asked me if I could build an eCommerce site for their family clothing business. Since I was busy and couldn&amp;rsquo;t manage the time to do it myself I forwarded the task to two of my fellow juniors.</description></item><item><title>All Kinds of "AAS" in Cloud Computing</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/cloud/all-aas-in-cloud-computing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/cloud/all-aas-in-cloud-computing/</guid><description>From an end users perspective, there are three kinds of aaS in cloud computing. By aaS I mean &amp;ldquo;as a Service&amp;rdquo;. They aaS-es are:
IaaS - Infrastructure as a service PaaS - Platform as a service SaaS - Software as a service As businesses are moving more towards the cloud, understanding the differences between the types of services and also knowing some of the service providers is essential.</description></item><item><title>Syllabus of ALL courses in a Software Engineering Bachelors/Undergrad Degree</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/software-engineering-curriculum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/software-engineering-curriculum/</guid><description>Before I started my undergrad in software engineering, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the slightest idea of what courses I would be offered. I assumed they would be called something like &amp;ldquo;Java&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;C++&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;networking&amp;rdquo;. To my surprise, there was not a single course that contained the name of a programming language.</description></item><item><title>draw.io - Best Online Prototyping Tool</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/draw-io/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/draw-io/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a free and awesome prototyping/wireframing/mockup UI tool, search no more, go to draw.io
There are a lot of prototyping tools available online but most of them are very annoying. Either they are paid or requires signing up.</description></item></channel></rss>