<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kali on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/kali/</link><description>Recent content in kali on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/kali/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>7 Vulnerable applications for practicing pen-testing</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/vulnerable-applications-for-practicing-pentesting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/vulnerable-applications-for-practicing-pentesting/</guid><description>The best way to learn security concepts is by doing it. But how to do it if you don&amp;rsquo;t know it? These vulnerable apps will make you learn and do it!
1. DVWA Damn Vulnerable Web App (DVWA) is a PHP/MySQL web application that is damn vulnerable.
The app is divided into sections for different types of vulnerabilities. The best thing about DVWA is it has lessons/guidelines on how to exploit a vulnerability.</description></item><item><title>Kali as a regular operating system</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</guid><description>If you are an aspiring pentester you should definitely use Kali Linux and make it your primary OS. Switching to a new OS can be a very hard decision to make. Concerns such as whether you can do your regular work may rise. It has been quite a while (3 years) since I am using Kali as my primary OS and here are my experiences with it.
If you are shifting from a Windows environment and have no prior experience with Linux operating systems it&amp;rsquo;s best not to move to Kali just yet.</description></item><item><title>How to be a hacker with Kali</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered Kali Linux and thinking about how you can hack with it, you probably can&amp;rsquo;t and you’re probably walking in the wrong direction.
Kali is not a magic OS that can hack everything. It is just an operating system that comes with preinstalled pentesting tools. Now, you really cannot expect a tool to do everything by itself. You need to understand when it works, where it works, and how it works.</description></item></channel></rss>