<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kali on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/kali/</link><description>Recent content in Kali on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/kali/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pentesting with Metasploit the Vulnerability Exploitation Tool (with Cheat Sheets)</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/sections/security-tools-cheatsheet/metasploit-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/sections/security-tools-cheatsheet/metasploit-cheatsheet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Metasploit is the ultimate penetration testing tool for offensive security. And it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to use that even you could claim to be a hacker just by running a few commands. Also, it is incredibly powerful as well. This guide is a general overview of how Metasploit can be used.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pentesting with Nmap the Network Testing Tool (with Cheat Sheets)</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/sections/security-tools-cheatsheet/nmap-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/sections/security-tools-cheatsheet/nmap-cheatsheet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nmap is a CLI based port scanner. As modern networking relies heavily on TCP ports, scanning these ports can expose valuable and critical data about a device on the network. These data can then be used to understand where vulnerabilities lie and how potential hackers can use them. Thus learning to port scan using Nmap is one of the first things a security researcher needs to grasp.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kali as a Regular Operating System</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are an aspiring pentester you should definitely use Kali Linux and make it your primary OS. Switching to a new OS can be a very hard decision to make. Concerns such as whether you can do your regular work may rise. It has been quite a while (3 years) since I am using Kali as my primary OS and here are my experiences with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to be a Hacker with Kali</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered Kali Linux and thinking about how you can hack with it, you probably can&amp;rsquo;t and you’re probably walking in the wrong direction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kali is not a magic OS that can hack everything. It is just an operating system that comes with preinstalled pentesting tools. Now, you really cannot expect a tool to do everything by itself. You need to understand when it works, where it works, and how it works.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>