<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WebDev on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/webdev/</link><description>Recent content in WebDev on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/webdev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Free Front end development tools for the non front end guy</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/free-front-end-dev-tools-for-non-front-guy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/free-front-end-dev-tools-for-non-front-guy/</guid><description>Front end development is hard if you&amp;rsquo;re not a designer. This list is a collection of tools that will help you speed up your front end workflow as a non front end guy. Lets make front end easy again!
Table of Contents Color palette Design practices Iconography Typography Animations &amp;amp; Effects Photos &amp;amp; videos Illustrations Utilities Color Palette Parametric colormixer - Generate your palette Css gradient - Beautiful gradients Colorsinspo - Pre made color palettes Color Hexa - Learn more information about colors Color Space - Generate nice color palettes, gradients, and matching color schemes Design practices Design checklist - Best design practices to follow Design System Repo - Curated list of designs for inspiration SaaS Landing Page - SaaS landing page inspirations Iconography IconStore - free vector icons by designers Tilda icons - icons for landing page Ikonate - customisable &amp;amp; accessible vector icons.</description></item><item><title>The curse of a good domain name</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/the-curse-of-a-good-domain-name/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/the-curse-of-a-good-domain-name/</guid><description>We always want a good domain name for our websites, right? The qualities that make a domain good are:
Short name Easy to remember Easy to spell Have a .com extension Doesn&amp;rsquo;t have hyphens/numbers But sometimes, having all of these together may come at a price.
Last week I got a call from my cousin who works at a private company. That company has a website that is managed by some software firm.</description></item><item><title>Why I switched back to Github pages from blogger.com</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/why-i-switched-back-to-github-pages-from-blogger.com/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/why-i-switched-back-to-github-pages-from-blogger.com/</guid><description>Previously I used to blog on Github pages with Jekyll. After I discovered blogger.com, I thought I could improve my blogging experience with it. So I made the switch and these were my reasons.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a suitable Jekyll theme for my blog. So I made one for myself. Not being a good UI designer, I made a pretty bad theme. With Blogger.com&amp;rsquo;s WYSIWYG editor I thought I could make a better looking site.</description></item><item><title>Fix bulma mobile view problem</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/fix-bulma-mobile-view-problem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/fix-bulma-mobile-view-problem/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with bulma for a while. Although the desktop rendering worked well, there were issues with the mobile view:
Problem There is like a white border on the right The screen is scrollable towards the right (which should not be) Problem Problem fix To fix this, add the following code
.columns { margin: 0; } With the above css it should render properly.
Problem fixed</description></item><item><title>Implementing google custom search bar in your site</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/implement-google-custom-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/implement-google-custom-search/</guid><description>Look at the top-right side of the page below, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a Google custom search bar. If you want to implement a search bar like this on your site, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place!
There are two ways you can implement the google custom search bar:
Simple implementation Custom implementation Simple implementation First go to cse.google.com/cse/ and click on New search engine.
Fill up:
sites to search (the URL of your site) name of the search engine (name it whatever you like) and click on Create.</description></item><item><title>Top 10 practical reasons to use Jekyll for your site/blog</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/reasons-to-use-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/webdev/reasons-to-use-jekyll/</guid><description>I wanted to make a site but I could not decide which building platform to choose from, Wordpress or Jekyll? On one hand I had the incredible power of Wordpress and on the other hand my love for GitHub pages with Jekyll. Finally, I thought I would love to push content to my repo in Github with the terminal. So I went with Jekyll.
But Jekyll seemed complicated. It was difficult to start with.</description></item></channel></rss>