<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Useful Docker commands</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/docker/useful-docker-commands/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/docker/useful-docker-commands/</guid><description>&lt;p>This guide is a shortlist of the only docker commands you will ever need. I keep on forgetting them, so let me just note them here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to verify news on social media</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/how-to-verify-news-on-social-media/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/how-to-verify-news-on-social-media/</guid><description>The narcissist photos and posts on Facebook do not bother me anymore. What does bother me is that people spread fake news and some idiots believe them. And at times I have been unlucky to be on the &amp;ldquo;idiot&amp;rdquo; side of things.
Why people make fake news? The opportunities are endless&amp;hellip;
Fulfill agendas (mostly political) To promote personal beliefs Make people biased towards something More likes and views, eventually leading to more revenue from ads It&amp;rsquo;s fun to spread rumors and see the world collapse&amp;hellip; Why people spread fake news?</description></item><item><title>Most Useful VScode shortcuts</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/most-useful-vscode-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/most-useful-vscode-shortcuts/</guid><description>VScode is my go-to editor now, but I keep forgetting all the nice shortcuts and commands. This article is a cheat sheet for me to look back when I forget my favorite ones.
VScode has different key bindings for each OS. Although most of the following should be general, if any of them isn&amp;rsquo;t working, the full bindings are available here for Linux, Windows, MacOS.
Editing Ctrl + X Cut line (no need for selection) Ctrl + C Copy line (no need for selection) Alt + ↓/↑ Move line up/down Ctrl + / Toggle line comment Ctrl + Shift + I Format document Ctrl + .</description></item><item><title>Parsing C++/Java/C# the Easy Way (with srcML)</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/parsing-cpp-java-cs-with-srcml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/parsing-cpp-java-cs-with-srcml/</guid><description>Recently I needed to parse C++ code to analyze some projects. I tried out several parsers (clang, libclang, cppast) but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get them to work for me. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find their documentation easy to understand. That&amp;rsquo;s maybe because I&amp;rsquo;m not so familiar with the C++ ecosystem. I suffered for quite a while until I found this awesome tool called srcML.
srcML is a lightweight tool for the exploration of source code that presents source code in an XML format.</description></item><item><title>Why even noobs should participate in CTFs</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-even-noobs-should-participate-in-ctfs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-even-noobs-should-participate-in-ctfs/</guid><description>A few days back Facebook held their first-ever CTF and Google also held theirs a few days later. Although I occasionally goof around with CTFs, I&amp;rsquo;m no expert at it. Despite this, I decided to take an attempt. I was skeptical at first but it turned out to be an awesome experience.
In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know what a CTF (capture the flag) is, it&amp;rsquo;s almost like a treasure hunt where you have to find a treasure by exploiting security loopholes.</description></item><item><title>7 Github repos that will make You Lol</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/github-repos-that-will-make-you-lol/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/github-repos-that-will-make-you-lol/</guid><description>Call me a nerd, but I find GitHub repositories to be entertaining. Here are some of my favorite ones that truly made me LOL. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to run any code or that sort of stuff. Just go through the READMEs.
1. hacker-scripts github.com/NARKOZ/hacker-scripts This is a story about a guy who left his job. His colleagues go through his legacy and found things they never imagined they would find.</description></item><item><title>Biological names used in computer science</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/biological-names-used-in-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/biological-names-used-in-computer-science/</guid><description>Once one of my biology teachers (boma Mizan :p ) said that biological names are used everywhere in technology. I suddenly recalled that memory and now I&amp;rsquo;m making a list of every biological name used in technology.
Amazon: Amazon is a rainforest in South America. Amazon is an American company focusing on e-commerce. Anaconda: Anaconda is a snake. Anaconda is a free and open-source distribution of the Python programming language for scientific computation.</description></item><item><title>Kali as a regular operating system</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</guid><description>If you are an aspiring pentester you should definitely use Kali Linux and make it your primary OS. Switching to a new OS can be a very hard decision to make. Concerns such as whether you can do your regular work may rise. It has been quite a while (3 years) since I am using Kali as my primary OS and here are my experiences with it.
If you are shifting from a Windows environment and have no prior experience with Linux operating systems it&amp;rsquo;s best not to move to Kali just yet.</description></item><item><title>How many programming languages should I learn</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/how-many-programming-languages-to-learn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/how-many-programming-languages-to-learn/</guid><description>Has it ever occurred to you, that you see a new programming language and you feel an urge to learn it? If love hobby programming then I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that you&amp;rsquo;ve had this dilemma of choosing whether to learn a language or not. Sometimes the fear of missing out makes us want to learn as many languages as possible. But how many languages do we actually need to learn?
Every language out there have their specialty that makes it worth learning.</description></item><item><title>How to be a hacker with Kali</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered Kali Linux and thinking about how you can hack with it, you probably can&amp;rsquo;t and you’re probably walking in the wrong direction.
Kali is not a magic OS that can hack everything. It is just an operating system that comes with preinstalled pentesting tools. Now, you really cannot expect a tool to do everything by itself. You need to understand when it works, where it works, and how it works.</description></item><item><title>How I accidentally visited a datacenter</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/how-i-accidentally-visited-a-datacenter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/how-i-accidentally-visited-a-datacenter/</guid><description>So, some of my friends were looking for a VPS for their research work. High config AWS or GCP is really expensive so they were looking for alternatives. That&amp;rsquo;s when our professor told them to meet a guy called Mahedi. They dragged me along to meet him and I&amp;rsquo;m glad that they did.
So Mahedi bhai works at BdREN (Bangladesh Education and Research Network). BdREN connects all the public Universities in Bangladesh through a fiber-optic network and provides fast internet and other cloud services.</description></item><item><title>5 reasons why Linux needs no antivirus</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-linux-needs-no-antivirus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-linux-needs-no-antivirus/</guid><description>So, maybe you have heard Linux PCs are super safe because they are not affected by viruses. Linux computers are almost immune to viruses. Yes, I said &amp;ldquo;almost&amp;rdquo; immune. But the percentage of PCs being affected is very less, even less than 1%. That is why people say that Linux does not need any antivirus. But why is that have you ever wondered? Here are the top 5 reasons why viruses do not affect Linux.</description></item></channel></rss>