<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Write Git Commit Messages</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/git/how-to-write-git-commit-messages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/git/how-to-write-git-commit-messages/</guid><description>A well-written git commit properly conveys what was done in the source code. As software engineering is a team project, being able to convey to others the intent of a commit is very important.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll give a short guideline on how to write commit messages.</description></item><item><title>10 Famous Computer Science Quotes</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/misc/famous-computer-science-quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/misc/famous-computer-science-quotes/</guid><description>Feed your mind with great quotes from the best computer nerds of all time. The following quotes are some of my favorite quotes that I shamelessly collected from the internet.
&amp;ldquo;Talk is cheap, show me the code.</description></item><item><title>7 Tips on How to Win Hackathons</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/misc/how-to-win-hackathons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/misc/how-to-win-hackathons/</guid><description>In 2018, I attended several hackathons. In all of those hackathons, our team managed to make it to the top 3 every time. We even managed to be a champion once. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll share some tips from my experience that I think can help you gain an edge in your next hackathon.</description></item><item><title>7 Vulnerable Applications for Practicing Pentesting</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/vulnerable-applications-for-practicing-pentesting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/vulnerable-applications-for-practicing-pentesting/</guid><description>The best way to learn security concepts is by doing it. But how to do it if you don&amp;rsquo;t know it? These vulnerable apps will make you learn and do it!
1. DVWA Damn Vulnerable Web App (DVWA) is a PHP/MySQL web application that is damn vulnerable.</description></item><item><title>13 Terminal Commands that you Don't Need but Deserve</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/terminal-commands-that-you-dont-need-but-deserve/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/terminal-commands-that-you-dont-need-but-deserve/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Linux terminal is not all boring and dull. Spice up your life with these fun and awesome commands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Awesome Terminal Tricks to Boost Your Productivity</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/awesome-terminal-tricks-to-boost-your-productivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/awesome-terminal-tricks-to-boost-your-productivity/</guid><description>If you are glued to the terminal, you may want to use the following tricks to improve your productivity. These have been a life saver to me. If you&amp;rsquo;re not a terminal user, these tricks will make you love the terminal again.</description></item><item><title>npm Commands for npm Noobs</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/npm-commands-for-npm-noobs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/npm-commands-for-npm-noobs/</guid><description>Since diving deeply into frontend development, I was having trouble adjusting with the node ecosystem, more specifically to the npm commands. I just keep on forgetting what the different npm commands do. So here&amp;rsquo;s my short notes on them.</description></item><item><title>Difference Between Bash, Shell &amp; Terminal</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/bash-vs-shell-vs-terminal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/bash-vs-shell-vs-terminal/</guid><description>People often incorrectly use the terms bash, shell and terminal interchangeably. Whether you are a Linux pro or noob, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve done it too. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you should know when you use these terms the next time.</description></item><item><title>Free Front End Development Resources for Everyone!</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/free-front-end-dev-resources-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/free-front-end-dev-resources-for-everyone/</guid><description>Front end development is hard if you&amp;rsquo;re not a designer. This list is a collection of tools that will help you speed up your front end workflow as a non front end guy. Lets make front end easy again!</description></item><item><title>Cases Used in Programming</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/cases-used-in-programming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/cases-used-in-programming/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard about following camel cases when naming functions and variables. There are more types of cases out there. In this post, we will discover other cases followed in naming conventions and where they are commonly used.</description></item><item><title>How I Suffered by not Doing Requirements Engineering</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/how-i-suffered-by-not-doing-requirements-engineering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/how-i-suffered-by-not-doing-requirements-engineering/</guid><description>Recently one of my relatives asked me if I could build an eCommerce site for their family clothing business. Since I was busy and couldn&amp;rsquo;t manage the time to do it myself I forwarded the task to two of my fellow juniors.</description></item><item><title>All Kinds of "AAS" in Cloud Computing</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/cloud/all-aas-in-cloud-computing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/cloud/all-aas-in-cloud-computing/</guid><description>From an end users perspective, there are three kinds of aaS in cloud computing. By aaS I mean &amp;ldquo;as a Service&amp;rdquo;. They aaS-es are:
IaaS - Infrastructure as a service PaaS - Platform as a service SaaS - Software as a service As businesses are moving more towards the cloud, understanding the differences between the types of services and also knowing some of the service providers is essential.</description></item><item><title>The Curse of a Good Domain Name</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/the-curse-of-a-good-domain-name/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/the-curse-of-a-good-domain-name/</guid><description>We always want a good domain name for our websites, right? The qualities that make a domain good are:
Short name Easy to remember Easy to spell Have a .com extension Doesn&amp;rsquo;t have hyphens/numbers But sometimes, having all of these together may come at a price.</description></item><item><title>How to Write a Research Proposal</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/how-to-write-a-research-proposal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/how-to-write-a-research-proposal/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are writing a research proposal, you&amp;rsquo;ll find the following tips helpful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Switched Back to Github Pages from Blogger.com</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/why-i-switched-back-to-github-pages-from-blogger.com/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/why-i-switched-back-to-github-pages-from-blogger.com/</guid><description>Previously I used to blog on Github pages with Jekyll. After I discovered blogger.com, I thought I could improve my blogging experience with it. So I made the switch and these were my reasons.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a suitable Jekyll theme for my blog.</description></item><item><title>Fix Bulma Mobile View Problem</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/fix-bulma-mobile-view-problem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/fix-bulma-mobile-view-problem/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with bulma for a while. Although the desktop rendering worked well, there were issues with the mobile view:
Problem There is like a white border on the right The screen is scrollable towards the right (which should not be) Problem fix To fix this, add the following code</description></item><item><title>Useful Docker Commands</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/docker/useful-docker-commands/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/docker/useful-docker-commands/</guid><description>&lt;p>This guide is a shortlist of the only docker commands you will ever need to know. I keep on forgetting them, so I&amp;rsquo;m noting them down here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Algorithms that I Learned</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/algorithms-i-learned/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/algorithms-i-learned/</guid><description>This is just a personal list of algorithms that I have learned over time. Since I keep on forgetting them, I decided I should make a list and review them from time to time. If you find the list helpful, thank me in the comments below.</description></item><item><title>How to Verify News on Social Media</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/how-to-verify-news-on-social-media/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/how-to-verify-news-on-social-media/</guid><description>The narcissist photos and posts on Facebook do not bother me anymore. What does bother me is that people spread fake news and some idiots believe them. And at times I have been unlucky to be on the &amp;ldquo;idiot&amp;rdquo; side of things.</description></item><item><title>Most Useful VScode Shortcuts</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/most-useful-vscode-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/most-useful-vscode-shortcuts/</guid><description>VScode is my go-to editor now, but I keep forgetting all the nice shortcuts and commands. This article is a cheat sheet for me to look back when I forget my favorite ones.
VScode has different key bindings for each OS.</description></item><item><title>Guidelines to Follow When Writing a Research Paper</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/research-paper-writing-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/research-paper-writing-guidelines/</guid><description>This article is not meant to be a complete guide for paper writing. It is just a cheat sheet for me to follow when I&amp;rsquo;m lost.
A research paper typically has the following sections:
Title Abstract Introduction Literature review Methodology Experiment/Results Acknowledgments (Optional) Conclusion References Appendices (Optional) 1.</description></item><item><title>How I Accidentally Published a Research Paper at IWOR (ICSE)</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/how-i-published-a-research-paper-at-iwor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/how-i-published-a-research-paper-at-iwor/</guid><description>In our final semester of university, we had a course called &amp;ldquo;Software Metrics.&amp;rdquo; Ths study of software metrics aims at measuring the properties of software. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like this course very much. It was theoretical and a bit boring.</description></item><item><title>Parsing C++/Java/C# the Easy Way (with srcML)</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/parsing-cpp-java-cs-with-srcml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/parsing-cpp-java-cs-with-srcml/</guid><description>Recently I needed to parse C++ code to analyze some projects. I tried out several parsers (clang, libclang, cppast) but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get them to work for me. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find their documentation easy to understand.</description></item><item><title>Why Even Noobs Should Participate in CTFs</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-even-noobs-should-participate-in-ctfs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-even-noobs-should-participate-in-ctfs/</guid><description>A few days back Facebook held their first-ever CTF and Google also held theirs a few days later. Although I occasionally goof around with CTFs, I&amp;rsquo;m no expert at it. Despite this, I decided to take an attempt.</description></item><item><title>Bare Minimum Multi-Tasking Guide for the Terminal with Tmux</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/multitasking-in-terminal-with-tmux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/terminal/multitasking-in-terminal-with-tmux/</guid><description>Have you ever-
SSHed to a server and felt the need of another terminal session because the current one was already running something? SSHed to a server to run a long-running process but couldn&amp;rsquo;t close the terminal because it would terminate the process?</description></item><item><title>7 Github Repos that will Make You LOL</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/git/github-repos-that-will-make-you-lol/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/git/github-repos-that-will-make-you-lol/</guid><description>Call me a nerd, but I find GitHub repositories to be entertaining. Here are some of my favorite ones that truly made me LOL. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to run any code or that sort of stuff.</description></item><item><title>Biological Names Used in Computer Science</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/misc/biological-names-used-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/misc/biological-names-used-in-technology/</guid><description>Once one of my biology teachers (boma Mizan :p ) said that biological names are used everywhere in technology. I suddenly recalled that memory and now I&amp;rsquo;m making a list of every biological name used in technology.</description></item><item><title>Kali as a Regular Operating System</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/kali-as-regular-os/</guid><description>If you are an aspiring pentester you should definitely use Kali Linux and make it your primary OS. Switching to a new OS can be a very hard decision to make. Concerns such as whether you can do your regular work may rise.</description></item><item><title>How Many Programming Languages Should I learn</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/how-many-programming-languages-to-learn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/how-many-programming-languages-to-learn/</guid><description>Has it ever occurred to you, that you see a new programming language and you feel an urge to learn it? If love hobby programming then I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that you&amp;rsquo;ve had this dilemma of choosing whether to learn a language or not.</description></item><item><title>How to be a Hacker with Kali</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/be-hacker-with-kali/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered Kali Linux and thinking about how you can hack with it, you probably can&amp;rsquo;t and you’re probably walking in the wrong direction.
Kali is not a magic OS that can hack everything. It is just an operating system that comes with preinstalled pentesting tools.</description></item><item><title>DSSE: A Software Engineering Research Group in Bangladesh</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/software-engineering-research-and-dsse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/research/software-engineering-research-and-dsse/</guid><description>If you want to know about research areas in Software Engineering and conferences/journals related to software engineering then this article is for you.
The Distributed Systems and Software Engineering (DSSE) group at the Institute of Information Technology (IIT) is an active group dedicated to Software Engineering research.</description></item><item><title>How I Accidentally Visited a Datacenter</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/cloud/how-i-accidentally-visisted-a-datacenter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/cloud/how-i-accidentally-visisted-a-datacenter/</guid><description>So, some of my friends were looking for a VPS for their research work. High config AWS or GCP is really expensive so they were looking for alternatives. That&amp;rsquo;s when our professor told them to meet a guy called Mahedi.</description></item><item><title>draw.io - Best Online Prototyping Tool</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/draw-io/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/software-engineering/draw-io/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a free and awesome prototyping/wireframing/mockup UI tool, search no more, go to draw.io
There are a lot of prototyping tools available online but most of them are very annoying. Either they are paid or requires signing up.</description></item><item><title>Image Clustering</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/machine-learning/image-clustering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/machine-learning/image-clustering/</guid><description>Clustering is a technique to group similar elements together. The following shows a simple program codebase is a small attempt to cluster colors in images.
At the heart of the program lies the K-Means algorithm. The source is available at github.</description></item><item><title>How Difficult is Programming</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/how-difficult-is-programming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/programming/how-difficult-is-programming/</guid><description>One of the first questions asked by beginners who want to start programming is, &amp;ldquo;How difficult is programming?&amp;rdquo; The answer in short is, learning a programming language is easy. Writing a good program is difficult.</description></item><item><title>Implementing Google Custom Search Bar in your Site</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/implement-google-custom-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/implement-google-custom-search/</guid><description>Look at the top-right side of the page below, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a Google custom search bar. If you want to implement a search bar like this on your site, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place!</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons Why Linux Needs No Antivirus</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-linux-needs-no-antivirus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/security/why-linux-needs-no-antivirus/</guid><description>So, maybe you have heard Linux PCs are super safe because they are not affected by viruses. Linux computers are almost immune to viruses. Yes, I said &amp;ldquo;almost&amp;rdquo; immune. But the percentage of PCs being affected is very less, even less than 1%.</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Practical Reasons to Sse Jekyll for your Site/Blog</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/reasons-to-use-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/reasons-to-use-jekyll/</guid><description>I wanted to make a site but I could not decide which building platform to choose from, Wordpress or Jekyll? On one hand I had the incredible power of Wordpress and on the other hand my love for GitHub pages with Jekyll.</description></item></channel></rss>