<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogging on DevRa</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/blogging/</link><description>Recent content in Blogging on DevRa</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/devra/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I Switched Back to Github Pages from Blogger.com</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/why-i-switched-back-to-github-pages-from-blogger.com/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/why-i-switched-back-to-github-pages-from-blogger.com/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously I used to blog on Github pages with Jekyll. After I discovered blogger.com, I thought I could improve my blogging experience with it. So I made the switch and these were my reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a suitable Jekyll theme for my blog. So I made one for myself. Not being a good UI designer, I made a pretty bad theme. With Blogger.com&amp;rsquo;s WYSIWYG editor I thought I could make a better looking site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I liked managing blog posts in the browser rather than with a text editor locally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The fact that my blog was in the cloud and I could access it from any PC was appealing. With Github pages I was limited to my local machine. Working from other PCs is possible but it required the hassle of git clones and git configs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blogger.com comes with a neat mobile app that makes writing on the go possible (even offline).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blogger.com has inbuilt support for comments and user analytics. In Github pages plugins (such as disqus and google analytics) were required.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Blogger seemed like the appropriate platform for me. But after publishing about 20 posts problems started popping out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top 10 Practical Reasons to Use Jekyll for your Site/Blog</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/reasons-to-use-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/devra/posts/web/reasons-to-use-jekyll/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wanted to make a site but I could not decide which building platform to choose from, Wordpress or Jekyll? On one hand I had the incredible power of Wordpress and on the other hand my love for GitHub pages with Jekyll. Finally, I thought I would love to push content to my repo in Github with the terminal. So I went with Jekyll.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>